<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>masters on Charlotte M. Jones-Todd</title>
    <link>https://cmjt.github.io/tags/masters/</link>
    <description>Recent content in masters on Charlotte M. Jones-Todd</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://cmjt.github.io/tags/masters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimating parameters of a void process using a Bayesian approach</title>
      <link>https://cmjt.github.io/project/void/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmjt.github.io/project/void/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project will involve using a Bayesian approach to estimate parameters of a void point process. No prior knowledge of point processes is required; however, a student should be comfortable with the concepts covered in STATS730 and STATS731.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodness-of-fit for point process models?</title>
      <link>https://cmjt.github.io/project/pp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmjt.github.io/project/pp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A set of locations in time and space is a point pattern: earthquake epicenters, burglaries, animal habitats. The arrangement of these points is generated by a combination of deterministic and stochastic processes. To adequately model data generated by such mechanisms, it is key that a framework is developed to correctly account for both the spatial and the temporal dependencies. Models that incorporate random fields are fast becoming the preferred tool of choice. These allow us to account for inherent variations and spatial dependencies without demanding knowledge of the generating mechanisms. However, we currently lack appropriate measure of fit for these models. This project will look at goodness-of-fit for a range of point process models, using simulation based approaches to better understand how different cross validation regimes affects inference. No familiarity with point processes statistics is needed; however, strong R programming skills are required and familiarity with C++ would be advantageous. Good grades in STATS310 and STATS330 would also be beneficial.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rewriting an RShiny application that implements virtual experiments in JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://cmjt.github.io/project/puzzle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmjt.github.io/project/puzzle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://statbiscuit.shinyapps.io/vested/&#34;&gt;vested&lt;/a&gt; is an Rshiny application that implements a number of different simulated experiments. The application is used in-course to aid in teaching experimental design to biostatistics students. This project would be to convert/rewrite vested (currently written in R) into JavaScript code. Although, much of the technical details are prescribed there is plenty of scope in the design, aesthetics, and layout of the application for creativity!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strong JavaScript coding skills. R/Rshiny skills desirable. Artistic skills a bonus! Good grades in CS335 and/or CS373 would also be beneficial.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What happens if we ignore self-excitement in point process models?</title>
      <link>https://cmjt.github.io/project/selfpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmjt.github.io/project/selfpp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Events cluster in time and space: tweets go viral, flurries of nearby earthquakes occur in quick succession. Temporal and spatial proximity are major factors in the chain reaction of events. However, how and why these spatiotemporal clusters form is much more complex: the mechanisms that generate clusters of events are often self-exciting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project will look at what happens when self-excitement is ignored. No familiarity with point processes is needed; however, strong R programming skills are required and familiarity with C++ would be advantageous. Good grades in STATS310 and STATS330 would also be an advantage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
